AHRIM HAN, PH.D.

SUMMARY

I am transitioning from academia to industry to work as a data scientist and machine learning scientist. Over the past 14 years, I have researched software engineering in computer science to improve software design and code quality using statistics and machine learning techniques. I have a special interest in finding business impacts by leveraging big data intelligence.

EDUCATION

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Ph.D. Computer Science 2013

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

M.S. Computer Science 2007

Sogang University

B.E. Computer Science 2004

Feb. 2000 - Feb. 2004

Feb. 2007 - Aug. 2013

Sept. 2004 - Feb. 2007

PROJECTS

Sentimental Analysis of Movie Reviews using a Deep Learning Neural Network (Springboard)

Mar. 2019 - July 2019

We have developed a deep learning model for identifying and classifying the sentiment expressed in texts of movie reviews as positive or negative using Python with Keras. We especially used a pre-trained embedding, Glove, for the Embedding layer in a Convolutional Neural Network model and discussed the overfitting.

Prediction of Scores for Public Schools in California (Springboard)

Oct. 2018 - June 2019

I applied many of the data science-related techniques for data wrangling, exploratory data analysis, data visualization, and machine learning modeling. I provided the prediction models using the regression and classification algorithms for finding the inferior schools that need help.

Efficient Refactoring Candidate Identification (Korea University)

Mar. 2008 - Apr. 2017

As a sole principal investigator, I developed an efficient refactoring recommendation system that helps software developers change code more easily. In order to increase the computational efficiency of the heavy computation when evaluating a large number of refactoring candidates, I developed the following methods.

- I developed a fast refactoring candidate assessment method using the graph-based approach and matrix computation. This sacrifices some degree of precision but significantly reduces the computation complexity, which can be helpful in analyzing large-scale software.
- I suggested the two-phased search-based refactoring identification method for the efficient search space exploration by predicting refactoring candidates with higher chances of quality improvement. Compared to the no-reduction approach, our approach could be 13.5 (max) times faster in time.

Improvement of Change-Proneness Prediction (KAIST)

Mar. 2006 - Feb. 2010

I developed a more accurate change-proneness prediction model to help software developers to focus their efforts on more critical maintenance activities. I devised the new behavioral dependency metrics to capture the dynamic aspects of the program, and the model accuracy (R-square) using these metrics is an 8% increase over the model using only program structural metrics.

EXPERIENCE

Springboard, Data Science Career Track - Student (Deep Learning Specialization)

Oct. 2018 - Aug. 2019

- Mastering skills in Python, SQL, data wrangling, data visualization, exploratory data analysis, and machine learning and deep learning methods.
- Performed two data science-related capstone projects: "Prediction of Scores for Public Schools in California" and "Sentiment Analysis of Movie Reviews using a Deep Learning Neural Network"

Korea University, Research Professor, Seoul, South Korea

Sept. 2013 - Apr. 2018

- Advised graduate students to develop research topics and conduct the experiments

 Application of Value of
- Awarded \$158,000 in grants from the National Research Foundation of Korea for my research projects, "Efficient Refactoring Candidate Identification"

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST), Graduate Researcher, Daejeon, South Korea

Mar. 2005 - Aug. 2013

- Actively performed my research project "Improvement of Change-Proneness Prediction" and implemented program structure analysis and metric measurement tools using Java and Python
- Mentoring and Taught in Computer Science courses: "Introduction to JAVA programming" and "Capstone Projects in CS

PUBLICATIONS

Two-phase Assessment Approach to Improve the Efficiency of Refactoring Identification, Ah-Rim Han, Sungdeok Change

IEEE Transactions on Software Engineering (TSE), Vol 44, No. 10, pp. 1001 - 1023, Oct. 2018

An efficient approach to identify multiple and independent Move Method refactoring candidates, Ah-Rim Han, Doo-Hwan Bae, Sungdeok Cha Information and Software Technology (IST), Vol. 59, pp. 53–66, Mar. 2015

SKILLS

DATA ANALYSIS, VISUALIZATION, AND MODELING: Pandas, Numpy, Scipy, Matplotlib, Pyplot, Seaborn, Scikit-Learn, Keras, Tensorflow, PySpark, NLTK STATISTICAL METHODS AND MACHINE LEARNING: Classification, Regression, Clustering, Hypothesis Testing, Deep Learning PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES AND TOOLS: Python, SQL, Java, R, Fortran, Assembly, Markdown, Latex, SPSS RESEARCH AREAS: Software Engineering, Refactoring, Software Quality Improvement, Software Design Measurement, Natural Language Processing